so I'm going to close with a composite
sketch of Jesus I need you to listen
like Adam he was the son of God like
Samuel he was only a boy when he
discovers his mission in the temple like
Joseph he was 30 years old when he came
into prominence like Joshua he crossed
the Jordan to lead 12 like Elijah he
provided drink for the thirsty like
Moses he entered the wilderness to
wander for for forty days like Daniel he
overcame the temptation of appetite like
job he refused the sin of presumption
like meshach Shadrach and Abednego he
refused to bow down before another dawn
like the man of God He healed a weather
hand like Eliezer he raised the dead and
multiplied the bread and helped lepers
like Ezekiel he preached to a stubborn
and rebellious people and spoke against
the abominations being done in the
temple like Josiah he exposed false
worship like Enoch he walked with God
like Moses he knew that his hour had
come he gathered the twelve to repeat
the covenant and sang a song before
going out to die alone like David he
crossed the brook kidron as his enemies
pursued him like David he was betrayed
by his close friend who eventually hung
himself like Joel he enters into a time
of trouble in the Garden of Gethsemane
like Joel he was tempted to think that
God had forsaken him like Joseph he was
sold for silver and deserted by his
brothers like Joseph with the butler and
the Baker he was placed between two men
one forgiving the other rejected like
Samson he was beaten bound and mocked
placed between two pillars bowed his
head and pushed and when he died there
was a great rumbling and he saved more
in his death and when he was alive like
Isaac he was given up for sacrifice like
Noah he was lifted up above the earth on
wood so that all men would be drawn to
him like Nehemiah he would not come down
for he had a great work to do
like Joel he prayed for his enemies like
Samson his death caused a great rumbling
in the earth like Elijah's dead bones
his death brought to life many who slept
in the grave like
he was in the belly of the earth three
days and three nights like David he
delivered a deadly blow to the head of
his enemy like Moses he was willing to
be blotted out of the book but was
resurrected from the dead like Samuel he
was called out of his sleep to serve as
priests in the house of God like Jonah
he stayed for 40 days like Nehemiah he
finished the work like Eliezer he was
raised into the heavens like Joseph he
was sent ahead to prepare a place for
his brothers like Daniel he interceded
on behalf of his people like Jacob while
he is away he is working for his bride
like Joseph he will investigate his
brethren before allowing them to enter
into the place he has prepared for them
like Moses he will descend from the
Mount upon an unexpected people
[Music]
as Moses part of the sea he will part
the sky and lead his people out of
bondage of the grave like Joshua he will
lead his people into the Promised Land
like David he will take his place as
rightful king like Solomon he will reign
in peace but for a thousand years like
Solomon he will answer all of our hard
questions like Gideon he will put down
the enemies of God at the end of the
millennium like Jaffa he will destroy
those who cannot speak the heavenly
language like Abraham he will be the
father of a great multitude and like
Joseph he will be reunited with his
loved ones
beloved Jesus is the center of our
scriptures
[Music]